Michael Smith

23310 SW Redfern PI Sherwood, OR, 97140 (503)-927-0643 smithmic23@outlook.com https://github.com/Msmith-I

About me

My name is Michael Dean Smith and I am a recent Oregon State graduate with a Bachelor's of Science in Computer Science. I have experience in multiple software languages as well as electrical engineering and mathematics. My ethnicity is American Indian and I am a member of the Tolowa Dee-ni tribe'.

EDUCATION

Oregon State University, Corvallis, OR

GPA: 3.16

Bachelor's of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

EXPERIENCE

AIAA USLI Rocket Payload Project, Corvallis, OR

Sept., 2021 - June, 2022

- I was part of the 2021-22 OSU USLI Rocket Payload subteam.
- It involved a year-long rocketry project and competition that was partnered with NASA.
- Required work involving hardware and software revolving around avionics as well as vision processing.
- My team successfully designed and created a payload that utilized a vision processing system to locate the rocket body post launch without the use of GPS.
- Competed nationally at the end of the year and finished 7th.

CollegeNet Inc., Portland, OR — Web Development Intern

June, 2020 - Dec. 2020

- I was part of the MyCoalition Dev team to manage and develop the company's college application website.
- The job included knowledge of basic Web Dev. computer languages such as HTML, JavaScript, and CSS. Also involved being fluent with Git and branch management.
- Used Jira and Gitlab as management sites.

SKILLS

- Software Languages: C++, C, Python, Java, JavaScript, AngularJS, HTML, CSS, SCSS, and Assembly.
- Knowledge of Jira, Github, Gitlab, and Git to manage project branches.
- Advanced hardware skills such as soldering and circuit construction
- Schematic development
- Electrical engineering
- Advanced critical thinking
- Wiring schematics
- Linux and Unix specialist
- Advanced debugging
- High-level Calculus and Physics
- Time management
- Teamwork and social skills
- Teaching and educational skills